I'll tell them we're here.
Oh, hello.
You're the new boy here, aren't you?
I think your room is right next to mine.
Let me help you with the bag.
You touched me!
You fool! You touched me!
You want to kill me?
You fool! You want to kill me?
You want to kill me.
Ooh, he touched me.
David, David, stop it at once.
Pull yourself together immediately.
A touch can kill.
You know that isn't true.
Now, control yourself.
A touch can kill!
Dr. Swinford's secretary is coming.
We're going to wait in his office.
Touch can kill.
Would you follow me, please?
Please sit down.
- Still 12:17.
- What?
It wasn't working the last time
we were here either.
What's the point of having a clock
which won't work?
He probably has a wristwatch.
- A Mickey Mouse wristwatch.
- Hello.
- Sorry to keep you waiting.
- Oh, it isn't important.
The important thing
is to get David settled.
I'll take him right up to his room
so he can unpack.
- Would you like to say goodbye now?
- I want to go up to his room with him.
I'm sorry. Visitors aren't allowed
in the rooms.
But surely I can see it?
The rooms belong to the students.
Goodbye, Mother.
Goodbye, darling.
Write often, won't you?
I'll miss you terribly.
I'll be right back.
Here we are, Mrs. Ferris.
This is David Clemens.
Hello, David.
Mrs. Ferris is our housekeeper.
Anything you want, just ask her.
See you in a little while.
Have you thought of anything else
since our talk a week ago,
anything about the nightmares, perhaps?
Nightmares?
Yes, I believe it was Mr. Clemens
who mentioned them.
They began when he was three
or four years old.
Oh, stomach aches.
His father would take him out,
buy him candy bars.
Those two would eat anything.
I had two little boys on my hands, really.
You do understand that neither his father
nor I ever hit or slapped him. Never.
This... This notion of his
about being touched,
it wasn't anything we did.
Hey! New guy in.
I want to see!
What's his name?
Hey, come on, let's go see him.
Where is he?
Hey, let's see the new kid.
Who is it?
It's Dr. Swinford.
I want a lock installed
in my door immediately.
No one will come in without your permission.
How do I know that?
That's one of our rules.
Things look in pretty good shape here.
Could we talk for awhile?
Dr. Swinford,
I submitted to extensive testing
and other nonsense
for two full days last week.
I'm here, I'll go along with the routine,
with the indignities.
But frankly, I don't care
for any more interviewing.
It's not interviewing.
It's just talking things over
so that perhaps I can help you.
After all,
that's what we're both here for, David.
All right.
Then let's say if I feel like talking to you,
I'll talk to you.
I'm available.
Dinner's not until 6:00.
You can go outdoors if you like.
I thought I told you, I loathe athletics.
Go for a walk.
A walk?
You may leave after classes if you want to,
just so long as you let me know
when you're going out.
What time is it now?
3:55.
May I see your watch?
Mediocre. Do you have any others?
I have a wristwatch.
Right now it's not working.
The clock in your office
isn't working either.
No. I haven't had time to have it fixed.
You'll have time now, won't you?
The time you'll save by not talking to me.
See you later, David.
Cow.
- Lisa...
- Cow, cow, cow.
Big black cow, big fat sow
- and how, how!
- Lisa?
Cow, cow, cow.
Would you like to look
at some pictures, Lisa?
So they sat,
so they sat,
and so they sat.
Big fat cow,
big black sow,
and how and how and how.
Well, where is he, the new inmate?
Maybe somebody warned him
about the food in this joint.
He has a terrible temper.
Why? What's the matter with him?
He must be exceptional, like the rest of us.
What does that mean?
You've been here a year and you don't know?
I hear that the new boy is tall and blonde,
my type.
You just touch him and he turns on you.
Hey, Kate, you can touch me anytime.
Is that all you will think about,
even when you're eating?
Maureen, I don't like celery soup
so I'm not going to eat it.
- Is that all right, Maureen?
- That's all right.
There he is.
Yeah!
Hello, David.
I'm Maureen. You're going to be at my table.
Would you like to come and meet everyone?
This is David Clemens who arrived today.
David, this is Sandra.
How do you do?
- And Carlos.
- Hiya.
Josette,
- and Simon...
- We've already met.
...and Kate.
- Hello.
Man, you classy dresser.
You're gonna be the best-dressed guy
in this school.
The rest are such slobs.
Do you play chess?
Will you play with me after dinner?
Oh, don't forget, after dinner
we have a meeting to discuss clothes.
Hey, what club are you gonna vote for?
I despise clubs.
Would you like to join our bowling team?
I despise bowling.
Oh, come on, man.
It's good exercise.
Exercise is for idiots!
Fine, David. That's very, very good.
- Who is it?
- It's Alan.
- What do you want?
- May I come in?
No, I'm busy.
Okay, I'll try some other time.
Hop, skip, jump.
I'm not a lump, I'm not a lump.
No, you're not a lump. You're a girl, Lisa.
I'm not a lump and I like to jump.
You're not a lump. You're not a lump.
You're a girl, Lisa.
I'm not a lump, I'm not a lump,
I'm not a lump, I'm not a lump...
All right.
You're Muriel.
Would you like to play a game, Muriel?
What would you like to do?
No, we can't go outside now.
It's nearly dinnertime.
Would you like to look out the window?
It's "with" not "wit." With.
Here, I'll show you.
Come on.
This is the way you spell "with."
W, I, T, H.
"With."
Why don't you comb your hair?
It looks fine in the morning
but right now it looks terrible.
Wait.
I'll play with you.
What would you like to play?
No, no, Lisa.
You mustn't write on the wall.
Give me the crayon, Lisa.
I'm sorry, Lisa.
I'm going to have to take the crayon
away from you.
John, John, be gone, be gone.
Enough of this stuffy stuff!
Are you angry with me, Lisa?
Angry, angry, wangry, wangry, angry.
Are you angry because I took your crayon?
You foo, you foo, it's you, it's you!
Foo, foo, foo, foo, foo!
John is a louse!
A big fat louse on a little gray mouse!
May I have a word with you?
Sure, David.
I've been studying your patient
and I've come to several conclusions.
I'd like to hear them.
Based on the fact that I've read
a great many books in your field.
Go on.
My diagnosis is adolescent schizophrenia,
undoubtedly of a chronic variety.
Do you follow me?
Yes, I do.
Well, then I shall continue.
Lisa has a very difficult time
with authoritarian figures.
It is extremely important
that you adopt an attitude
of permissiveness with her.
Therefore, you shouldn't have
taken away her crayon
even though she marked the wall.
John, John, come away, today, today.
I'd like to talk to you
some more about this, David.
I'll see you later.
You touched me? Why did you do that?
Why did you do that, you big fat fool?
I'm sorry, I forgot.
Why did you... You want to see me dead!
You want to see me dead, don't you?
Don't you?
I made a mistake, David.
You...
You coarse, clumsy, stupid fool!
You hate me.
Oh, he hates me.
Hi, come on in.
Why is it every time I stop here
to tell you I'm going out,
you ask me to come in?
Where are you off to?
A walk.
I feel like a walk myself.
You mind if I join you?
I was told you made a friend.
Friend?
Olga says you were talking to Lisa.
I talk to her merely
because her case interests me.
I see.
My ability to relate,
or any other psychiatric term you might use,
simply does not apply to me.
What do you find so funny?
I take particular pains not to use
psychiatric terms
yet you accuse me of doing it.
Well, all the others did.
All the idiot psychiatrists
my mother dragged me to.
Frankly, you experts devote too much time
to nonsense like dreams.
Do you dream often?
I had my clock-execution dream last night.
Well, we've had our little walk.
You satisfied?
I'd like to hear about your dream.
I thought you would.
The dream is always the same.
I've had it many times,
only the victim changes.
There's a huge clock with a huge hand,
the edge of which is very sharp,
like a razor.
There are holes in the face of the clock
with heads sticking through.
I'm pulling on the clock hand
with all my strength.
I pull the blade closer and closer.
It touches the victim's neck, cuts through,
I continue to pull the blade around the clock
until all the heads are cut off.
My victims are executed 12 times.
That's all.
Who are the victims?
John was the victim last night.
Who knows? Maybe tonight it will be you.
Hello, kiddo. So alone.
Hello.
Kiddo?
Kiddo, hello.
Me, the same. Lisa, the name.
Me, the same.
David, the name.
Look at me. What do you see?
What do you see?
Lisa, I see,
staring at me.
Don't touch.
All else will do, but please no such.
- Foolish talking, foolish squawking.
- Don't touch.
No such.
No such, no touch.
You're welcome.
Hi. Come on in.
Well, you've won the battle.
I'm in your office.
I didn't know we were having a battle.
- Want to sit down?
- No, I'm not staying.
I merely came to find out
if you've analyzed my dream.
No, I couldn't do that
without talking with you.
Typical psychiatrist's dodge!
You don't like psychiatrists much?
They think they have all the answers.
That's one thing I'm sure I haven't got.
I've interviewed a few of your colleagues.
Of course they thought
they were interviewing me.
- I'd like to hear about them.
- Yes, I'm sure you would.
I'm here to find out what you thought
about my dream.
What did you think about it?
Don't play Dr. Freud,
answering one question by asking another.
Go ahead, say it.
The dream proves I'm crazy.
No, it doesn't.
I presume that comes
under the heading of "reassurance."
Give the kid comfort and support.
I think I'm crazy.
Aren't you going to tell me anything
about my dream?
You sounded angry,
cutting off John's head that way.
A brilliant analysis.
You're terribly afraid of death, aren't you?
Aren't you?
Now who's playing Freud?
Go on.
It shows in your dream in two ways.
First, you're killing your enemies,
which will make you feel safer.
And second, you're pulling on the blade
so that you control life and death.
I wish you'd stay.
I know you do, Doctor.
David! David!
Look at me.
Who do you see? Who do you see?
Lisa I see, looking at me.
David, David, here we are.
Come away, far, far.
Not now, not today,
I say...
Some other day.
Lisa, why must we rhyme?
It's so hard and it takes so much time.
Funny David, can't you see?
Rhyming stops her, she then can't be.
That's why you rhyme!
You don't have to be Muriel when you rhyme!
Lisa! Come back!
Come back, I'll rhyme.
I'll rhyme, this time.
Rhyme, time, slime, rhyme!
Don't touch me.
Be careful,
don't touch me!
Lisa, Muriel, I warn you!
Don't touch me.
Been here long?
You haven't had your clock fixed.
Not yet.
Have you got your wristwatch
with you today?
Uh-huh.
It's probably a piece of clumsy junk.
How come you don't have a watch?
There isn't one in existence I'd want to own.
They're all grossly inaccurate.
Have you ever thought of the possibility
of a radio-controlled clock?
A radio alarm clock?
No, no, no, I mean one that...
This must be strictly confidential.
Everything we say is between us.
I plan to construct a masterpiece.
A combination of utterly precise instruments
put together in a perfect pattern.
My idea is this.
Everyone would wear a clock receiver
which would be tuned in
to a central electronic device.
Through this device they would
constantly be kept aware
of the exact time.
If they were interested.
It's an ingenious idea,
but I don't think many people are interested
in constantly having the exact time.
- I am.
- Why?
Time goes on and on, we can't stop it!
It never stops!
Second by second, minute by minute,
it's cutting off our heads!
- Like your dream?
- No. Yes!
It starts the minute we're born
and just keeps on going.
There's nothing we can do about it.
You're gonna die, Alan.
Do you know you're going to die?
Yes, I know.
Aren't you afraid?
Sure, sometimes. We all are.
If we could only stop time we could be safe.
We can't stop time, David.
All we can do is use it.
It's not only time that brings on death.
It's a lot of other things, too.
Not if we're careful!
Careful?
Yes, nobody get near me.
Not let anyone near me,
not let anyone touch me.
Not anyone let hurt me.
I think you mean hurt inside you,
in your heart, in your guts,
not where you bleed.
Where you feel.
No, I don't know what you're talking about.
Other people can make you feel pain,
can make you suffer, turn on you,
laugh at you...
No! I will not let them.
I will not let anyone touch me.
We can't add to the time allotted to us,
we can't even add a second to it.
All we can do is be alive in it.
Alive! Not numb inside.
We take a chance when we open up
and love another person.
What's wrong, Lisa?
Everyone's waiting for you.
She'd better make up her mind right now
or we'll miss the train.
We'll see all the Christmas decorations.
We're going to all the big stores.
Will you hold my hand
the whole time, Maureen?
I get nervous in crowds.
Don't you want to go, Lisa?
No, no.
Snow and ice, ice and snow. No! No!
Remember, we looked out the window?
There's no snow today.
Foolish talking, foolish squawking.
David, stay. We'II play, we'll play.
I can't stay.
But I'll walk while we talk.
No squawk talk, no talk squawk.
We'll walk, we'll walk.
Walk us two?
Me and you.
You and me, me and you,
walk us two.
If you just sit here,
we'll go buy your tickets.
- You shouldn't smoke.
- Why not?
'Cause it makes you look too tough.
I am tough.
Do you want to make something out of it?
- Hmm?
- Certainly not.
Who's that girl?
Whoever she is, she's very rude.
Holly golly, golly holly.
Golly holly, holly golly.
She's nuts. Must be from that school.
Beat it, damn it!
What the hell do you think you're doing?
- You want a punch in the jaw?
- Don't touch me.
Excuse her, please.
She was admiring your family.
- She's not normal.
- Lf you're normal, who wants to be normal?
Come on, David.
Come on. Let's go.
We'll wait for the train outside.
Bunch of screwballs! Spoiling the town!
Bunch of screwballs spoiling the town.
A bunch of screwballs...
A bunch of screwballs
spoiling the town!
A bunch of screwballs spoiling the town!
- A bunch of screwballs spoiling the town!
I'm going out for a walk.
I presume you've noticed me
playing chess with Simon?
He's not much competition.
Do you know something?
Lisa gets irritated every time
she sees me with Simon.
I think she's jealous.
Maybe.
Perhaps I'm getting through to
her feelings, to use your word.
Quite possibly.
Where did you get this?
In Rome, a long time ago.
Corny stuff you keep around here.
Sometimes Lisa acts so silly,
all that jumping around and rhyming.
She has no choice.
Sickness makes people do things
they don't want to do.
If they get better,
then they're free to do as they please.
They have a choice.
Compulsive versus non-compulsive?
Why use technical terms?
Poaching on your territory?
Civilians not allowed
to utter the sacred words?
You sound awful angry.
If "they" get better then they will
be allowed to do as "they" please!
What is this "they" routine,
when you mean me?
That's right, me.
I'm a real compulsive nut, aren't I?
Let's stick together, shall we?
Let's be each other's friend.
I play the piano. Will you listen to me play?
I don't like music.
Oh.
Game, game,
boy, poy.
Chess, mess,
chess, mess.
I can't stand her.
She can't help it.
She's a very sick girl.
Hello, kiddo.
Kiddo, hello.
David, David, look at me.
Who do you see? Who do you see?
Say to me what you see.
I see a girl,
who looks like a pearl.
A pearl of a girl.
John! John!
John, I'm a girl, a girl, a pearl of a girl!
Hiya!
Who you waiting for?
My son.
Are you a mother?
You look more like a sister.
I am Mrs. Clemens.
David "Hands Off' Clemens!
No kidding!
I think you're just about the cutest mother
I ever seen around here.
My God, how did David get
such a sexy mother?
Why don't you just go...
Go talk to someone else?
Oh, look at the broads in this place.
Why would I talk to them?
Old hens, all zipped up in their girdles.
- Will you go away?
- Oh, please, don't say that.
I'm so Ionely.
- No one ever come to see me.
- Oh?
See, my mother, she works so hard.
- All night, even.
- Oh.
She a very hard worker, and very tiring.
- What does your mother do?
- She's a hooker.
You know, a hustler.
She walks up the streets
and she sees a guy and she...
Never mind. I don't want to hear it.
Darling, I thought you would never come!
Hello, Mother.
What took you so long? Come and sit down.
You look pale. You've been eating enough?
You never write anymore.
Where's Father?
Chicago, business meeting.
- Did you get the pajamas I sent?
- Yes, thank you.
I don't want thanks.
Just a line to let me know they got here,
that's only good manners.
A boy I see, who looks like me.
I see me, Lisa.
Muriel? Muriel.
Poor child. What's wrong with her?
Schizophrenic.
You know, crazy.
Doesn't it upset you to be around
children like that?
Why should it? I'm crazy, too.
Don't say that. You have some problems...
I've got bats in my belfry,
otherwise I wouldn't be here.
How are you getting along
with Dr. Swinford?
Alan's okay.
You call him Alan? Not very respectful.
He doesn't care about
all that respectful crap.
David, your language!
What's a boy like that doing in this school?
He's crazy, too.
I mean, it's so expensive.
A welfare agency put him in here
after he knocked up 13 girls.
That's what he says.
In my opinion, he has delusions of grandeur.
Tell me all about school.
Nothing to tell.
Are you getting good grades?
I told you, they don't grade you here.
But how do you know
if you're at the top of your class?
It doesn't matter.
Of course it matters.
Why?
- There's that bastard, John.
- David!
David, aren't you making any friends?
I'm sure there are some nice boys here.
What do you mean by nice?
A milksop who has good manners?
David, you never used
to talk to me like that.
What makes you think
that I ever really talked to you at all?
When people talk,
it means they say what they really feel.
All you ever do is toss words around.
- What do you wanna do this afternoon?
- Nothing.
Well, I came all the way out here,
two hours in the traffic,
just to take you somewhere.
You're not being very grateful.
Come on, we'll do whatever you wanna do.
What a hypocrite you are!
You know damn well
we'll do what you want to do!
We always have!
- Where did you get these?
- I bought them.
- For yourself?
- Mmm-hmm.
"When all at once I saw a crowd
"A host of golden daffodils"
It was in our English book.
Well, what did you want to talk to me about?
Your parents are insisting
on taking you out of the school.
You mean they...
It was my mother, wasn't it?
I spoke to your father, also. He agrees.
My father's a marshmallow.
Inside, where you're always talking about.
The other day when your mother was here,
did anything special happen?
No.
Well, she's just not used
to having her sweet little boy
talk back or have an idea of his own.
I think she must've found me
under a cabbage.
I can't imagine her.
It was a rotten afternoon.
Next time I'll just have to cover up more.
It's what I've been doing all my life.
It's no solution, is it?
No, it isn't.
Parents don't like you when you're sick.
If you start to get well...
Better?
They don't like you, either.
It takes time for a family
to adjust to changes.
Well, it's almost the end of the term.
I think I ought to stay till then.
I think you ought to stay
a good deal longer than that.
Your father's coming
to take you home today.
Today?
But you're not going to let them
take me away?
I should've told you long before this
but I hoped I could make them
change their minds.
- I said you're not going to let them.
- You're their son.
I have no legal way of stopping them.
Sure.
I come, I go.
What the hell do you care?
I care.
Well, another little scramble-brained
bastard will come in tomorrow
so you won't lose a penny.
Do you think I like you
because I'm being paid to?
Oh, well,
I'm finally getting out of this looney bin.
God, how I hate this place. I just loathe it.
Your parents are doing this
against my advice.
Oh, I'm grateful to my parents!
Because they have the sense to realize
their mistakes, which is more than you have.
What mistakes?
Alan Swinford, headshrinker.
Do you know something?
You'd do a lot better delivering laundry.
It would give you a feeling of being of use
instead of
interfering in people's lives.
How have I interfered?
By the asinine idiotic questions
you're always asking!
Why do you keep asking these questions?
Why can't you stop, you...
Why can't you stop?
It's all right about the clock.
It can be fixed.
Will you please cut out
that understanding stuff?
What do I have to do?
Smash every damn thing in this office
before you'II fight back?
You mean fight back against your parents?
I did.
Believe me, I did.
Perhaps they'II reconsider
and change their minds.
If they do, I hope you'll come back.
Don't hold your breath.
Stuart, carve another piece
of roast beef for David.
He's hardly touched
the piece he has now.
David, you've got to eat.
I told you I'm not hungry.
But I planned this whole dinner
just for you, all your favorites.
You love biscuits. I made them myself.
Grace, put a biscuit on
David's plate, please.
Darling, try the biscuit while it's hot.
I spoke to the headmaster
at West Hill Academy.
They have openings in both
the junior and senior classes for next fall.
They want you to take some exams
so they'll know where you belong.
I am not going to West Hill Academy.
Of course you are. Don't be silly.
Would you rather go
to a public high school?
What kind of college preparation
can he get in a public school?
It prepared me.
Oh, whoever heard of the college
you went to?
I want David to go to an Ivy League school.
So you can tell everybody
that your son is going to Princeton?
Why shouldn't my son have the best?
I never did.
No decent clothes.
Couldn't even invite anybody into my house.
Old wicker furniture in the living room.
- You invited me in.
- Oh, you...
My family didn't count socially,
but your mother was kind enough
to marry me anyway.
Well, I've brought you
a long ways away from wicker furniture!
Lovely manners your father has.
It's terrible for me when you're not here.
Your father's so...
He's no companion.
Will you shut up about my father?
- David...
- Just shut up!
Remember I told you?
David went home to his own house.
That's right, he went with a man.
He went home with his father.
This is another way of spelling his name.
The way he spells it, remember?
This is his last name.
Clemens.
Can you print your last name?
Brandt.
B, R, A, N, D, T.
Brandt. Now try it.
David, you can't just stay here
in your room all the time.
Not eating, not talking to anybody.
You've got to get out and do things.
Listen, I've got a wonderful idea.
You and I and your mother
drive to California this summer,
take a look at the countryside. Good idea?
They say it's a great big beautiful country.
When I was your age I never went anywhere.
My father just didn't give a damn about me.
He just didn't care.
Frankly, he wasn't the greatest guy
in the world.
When you were born,
that made me a father and I was so proud.
The nurse held you up
and your eyes looked so new.
I wanted to make the world over
so those eyes could never see
anything that...
So that nothing ever could scare you.
Or disappoint you.
What is it you're so scared of, David?
When did it first start?
If it's something I did, I'm sorry.
Do you remember when you were little
all the toys you had in here?
The cars and trucks and stuffed animals.
David, do you remember
a fireman's helmet that I bought for you?
When you were little, you know,
you thought I was just about it.
Listen, if I take off next week,
would you like to go somewhere with me?
Just the two of us.
Drive up to Vermont.
Maybe even go camping?
You don't have to answer me now, but
I sure would love it.
I mean, just the two of us, you know.
Well, think about it, huh?
Why, David, hello. Come on in.
- I have to see Alan immediately.
- Okay, I'll get him.
Hello, David. Come on in.
I left home.
My parents don't know.
I'll have to call them. You understand why.
I won't go home.
That's all right.
I didn't have anywhere else to go.
I just came here.
I'm glad.
Hello, kiddo.
Kiddo, hello.
David. David, look at me.
What do you see? What do you see?
I see a girl who looks like a pearl.
A pearl of a girl.
I'm a girl. A girl, a pearl of a girl.
So I just packed my bags
and left in the middle of the night.
I walked to the station.
And there was this woman sitting there.
Colored woman.
She had this boy with her. It was her son.
And they were just sitting there
waiting for the train.
She had her arm around him, and, uh...
They were so peaceful.
She really liked that boy, I could tell,
because of the way she held him.
And I pretended that I was her son, too.
I just felt like being her son.
Strange, isn't it?
I don't think it's strange at all.
I spoke to your parents on the phone.
We talked for a long time.
It's all right.
They've agreed to let you stay.
I hate my parents.
We can hate and love people
at the same time.
- I don't see how.
- You will.
When you get to know your parents better
you'll understand that they had parents, too.
Strains and pressures, fears, failures.
My father has a lot of money.
He's a success,
but it's not a success inside.
Tell me, what happened at home?
It's depressing.
I guess it's funny, too.
Both maybe.
We were having dinner...
I prefer sculpture
that challenges your intellect, don't you?
No, not necessarily.
Such an unoriginal subject.
I don't mind.
I don't mind, either.
I rather like it.
I rather like it, too.
Lisa, come down.
Lisa?
Look, Mommy! Look at that girl!
Lisa, come down.
Young lady.
- Young lady, come down from there at once!
- No, no. Please, please, let me.
I'm sorry, I should've watched her.
Come on, Lisa.
It's time to go back to the school
and see John. John's waiting for us.
Come on, give me your hand.
That's it, give me your hand.
We'II come back
and visit some other day. Yes.
Now, come on, I've got you.
Put your foot down.
Come on, sweetie.
That's it. I've got you. All right?
Now, let's go see John.
- Did you get these in the backyard?
- Mmm-hmm.
Maybe I'll put some in my room. Only...
Only what?
The kids. They think that...
Have you ever been to a freak show?
At a circus?
Couple of times when I was a kid.
I went once when I was about eight.
Tell me about it.
There was this person, George-Georgina,
half man, half woman.
Half of its...
Its/his face had a beard on it,
the other half was smooth.
And it had a breast on one side, too.
And I got so scared,
I yelled and I ran right out of the tent.
I remember lots of times my mother
used to tell people
how George-Georgina scared me.
They used to laugh.
But it wasn't funny to you.
Well, I was just a little kid.
Wouldn't bother me now.
I noticed you got the clock
in your office fixed.
Mmm-hmm.
Maybe it was a good idea
I smashed the glass.
Gave you the push you needed
to get it fixed.
I guess it did.
I'm gonna put those flowers in my room,
I don't care what the kids think.
Doesn't really matter, does it?
No. The important thing is
what I think of myself.
- Here's one we could use.
- That's France, stupid.
The point of the party is Paris.
A night in Paris.
May I remind you
that Paris is the capital of France.
- Hey, we've got enough.
- Come on, let's go hang them up.
So warm, so nice, no snow, no ice.
Warm and nice, no snow, no ice.
David, David, here you are.
Come away far, oh, far.
Someday we'II go away.
Someday to the clean white sand.
And...
And, uh...
Lisa.
It's hard to rhyme.
Let me talk to you plain and straight.
Please trust me.
This time you rhyme.
You rhyme this time.
It's hard.
I can't. I really can't.
Don't go away!
David, David, you look nice.
Not like snow, not like ice.
You didn't go away.
You trust me.
You really trust me.
The other day
I wanted to ask you something.
And I just couldn't.
When you're ready, you will.
- I think I could now.
- What?
Well, it's about...
Do you think that maybe someday
if I work very hard
that I could get into medical school?
Maybe.
I haven't made up my mind about a specialty.
I thought maybe
I could be a psychiatrist, like you.
Maybe.
You know a lot more than you let on,
don't you?
The clock has a big hand
and
a small hand.
That's right. It's the same word, hands.
What do you want?
Do you want me to tell your fortune?
I wonder what your fortune is.
There's supposed to be a line for happiness
and a line for love.
I don't believe in palmistry.
Of course, anything's possible.
You do have a very long happiness line.
Can't stand it! Ears can't take it!
Do you really hate music? Good music?
Let me play a Bach prelude for you.
Please.
All right, let's leave.
It's very good.
Sign your name to it,
so they'II know it's yours.
No, no. I mean sign your name on the poster.
That's right.
Muriel and Lisa are you.
You are Lisa and Muriel.
Now look who's here.
Does that kid have to follow you
everywhere you go?
She's okay, she won't bother us.
Now, you've got be quiet and pay attention.
Go on, finish the piece.
You stop that! Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Now look what you've done!
Go on, get out of here! Leave us alone!
David, navid, lavid, savid, tavid, David!
París, it's where I'd like to be
Chérie, chéríe, chérie
When we are in Paris
We'll kíss, we'II dance, we'II ooh la la la
We'll ooh la la la...
Maureen. Maureen.
Have you seen Lisa?
- No, I thought she was with you.
- No.
Maybe she's in the art room.
I'll take a look.
I told her to keep quiet.
She got mad and she ran out of the room.
- How long ago?
- Maybe half an hour.
Nowhere. Been to every room, the attic.
She's not in the building.
She can't have gotten far.
We'll cover the neighborhood.
- Someone's sure to have seen her.
- I'd better get Ben and Donald.
- I'll come, too. I wanna help look for her.
- Okay.
Go to bed, David. It's almost morning.
The minute I hear from John,
the minute I hear that they've found her,
I'll come up and tell you.
She might've wandered for miles.
Somebody might've picked her up.
God, I hope nobody picked her up.
The conductor said she rode into town.
By his description,
it could've been anyone.
No, it was Lisa.
You know...
You run away,
you don'tjust run away from something,
you run to something.
I know because I did that
the night I came here. I came back.
The museum.
The statue, remember?
I told you what she did.
- How could she find her way up there?
- She might have.
It's better than sitting here.
Get yourjacket.
I'll get the car up.
Lisa?
Lisa!
David.
You were nice to Simon
and you were mean to me.
I'm sorry.
Lisa,
you didn't rhyme
and you're not Muriel.
You're you.
Lisa, Muriel,
the same.
I'm me.
Let's go back to school now.
Take my hand.
Lisa, take my hand.